Sebastian Durandeu

Senior Software Engineer

London, N22, UK

1 +44 07427 719875

<u>sebastian.durandeu@gmail.com</u>

sdurandeu s

sebadurandeu

in sebastiandurandeu

Download as PDF

About Me

For 10+ years I've helped multiple Fortune 500 companies and startups build software solutions acting as full-stack developer, team lead and customer advocate. I have experience leading both on-site and distributed teams, making sure delivery goes according to plan and meets customer expectations. I believe my greatest strengths are my organization and attention to detail and best practices, together with excellent communication and reporting skills.

Experience

Southworks

Apr 2017 - Ongoing

Software consultancy firm specialized in helping companies adopt emerging technologies

Principal Software Engineer (London, UK)

Managed remotely a development team (5) to re-engineer a core statistics system from an US sports company and migrate it to the cloud (Microsoft Azure). Project design and planning. Main interface with the customer with regular on-site meetings for progress reporting. 1-on-1 meetings with developers for performance evaluation and mentoring.

Vinti

Apr 2016 - Mar 2017

FinTech startup - mobile app to solve everyday payments with a smart, user-friendly approach (more info in Spanish <u>here</u> and <u>here</u>)

Lead Engineer (Buenos Aires, Argentina)

Joined the co-founders as first employee to build and grow the payments platform. Full-stack engineer in charge of the Cordova/Ionic mobile app with a Node.js backend hosted in Amazon Web Services. Infrastructure design, maintenance and security audits. Also worked on product design, customer support and sales.

Southworks

Oct 2007 - Apr 2016

Software consultancy firm specialized in helping companies adopt emerging technologies

Principal Software Engineer (Buenos Aires, Argentina)

- Member of the Delivery team, in charge of resource allocation, project forecasting and monitoring. Recruiting and performance reviews of developers. Support account managers with new opportunities (pre-sales).
- Technical lead for different projects, across a 2.5-year timespan, developing and maintaining one of Microsoft's core marketing and documentation sites. The site had strong scalability and availability requirements and runs end-to-end using Microsoft Azure cloud service.
 Project scope included developing a documentation publishing and maintenance workflow and a continuous deployment infrastructure.
- Worked on the front-end for a new videos platform for SharePoint Online Services (now Office 365). The front-end included both a SharePoint app and a Windows 8 app and interacted with the SharePoint APIs.

Lead Software Engineer (Redmond, US)

• 3 months on-site at Microsoft headquarters working in the engineering team of the <u>Azure Marketplace</u>. Developed a continuous testing infrastructure based on Selenium and the TeamCity API to validate partners' listings and integrations.

• Helped Microsoft internal teams create and deliver <u>keynote demos ()</u> to be presented live for thousands of attendees during the <u>//BUILD/ 2012</u> and <u>2013</u> developer conferences. Provided support to presenters from the backstage.

Software Engineer (Buenos Aires, Argentina)

- Create content for Microsoft Developer and Platform Evangelism (DPE) Division for evangelizing Microsoft latest development technologies and frameworks (mainly around the Microsoft Azure Platform and the Microsoft Web Stack). Some of these projects involved writing technical guidance, that shows how to implement common scenarios and get to working solutions (like the <u>Microsoft Azure Training Kit</u>). Others involved creating reusable content, like APIs and toolkits, to help the developer community adopt new technologies and frameworks (examples are <u>DinnerNow</u> or an <u>OData API for Visual Studio Team Foundation</u> Service).
- Help a top pharmaceutical company develop a company-wide identity platform, based on claims-based identity and Microsoft ADFS (Active Directory Federation Services).

Technical Writer and Developer (Buenos Aires, Argentina)

• Created technical guidance (hands-on labs) for Microsoft latest development technologies and frameworks.

Huenei Consulting

Jun 2007 - Oct 2007

Development Intern (Buenos Aires, Argentina)

Development using Oracle PL/SQL for insurance-related software projects.

Side Projects

Toptal Member

Premium Freelance Platform

Jan 2016 - Ongoing

Completed the recruiting process and joined the platform, but did not apply for any project due to lack of availability. Profile here.

TiendaNube Rating Store App

TiendaNube provides a complete e-commerce platform for small retailers (similar to Shopify or Magento)

Designed and developed an app that allows users to add a rating and comments widget to their store. The app can be installed through the <u>app store</u> for a monthly fee and is available both in Spanish and Portuguese. It is developed in Node.js (Express) and MongoDB and hosted in Amazon Web Services.

Technical Book Reviewer

Reviewed technical books for Packt Publishing: <u>Azure Storage Essentials</u> and <u>Implementing Azure Solutions</u>.

Blog

Personal blog in Spanish including software development and other stuff (Deprecated)

Education

Software Engineer

2004 - 2011

University of Buenos Aires - Grade +8/10

One year as teaching assistant in Dața Oṛgañiĝațiõñ class. Some topics covered by the subject included data organization structures and algorithms (B-trees, Hashes, etc.), text retrieval engines and data compression.

Skills

The technologies and frameworks I've worked most with include:

- .NET Framework and the Microsoft Web Stack (ASP.NET MVC, Entity Framework, Web Api, etc.)
- Cloud Platforms and Services (Microsoft Azure and Amazon Web Services)
- Web standards (HTTP, REST, HTML5, etc.)
- Javascript and Node.js
- Hybrid mobile apps (Cordova, Ionic, etc.)
- Database systems (SQL Server, MySQL, MongoDB, SQL Server Analysis Services, etc.)
- Continuous Integration and Delivery automation (TeamCity, Selenium, PowerShell, etc.)

Languages **English** Bilingual - Certificate in Advanced English ($\underline{\mathsf{CAE}}$) Basic - Diplôme d'Études en Langue Française B1 (<u>DELF</u>) French **Spanish** Native Misc Three books I've read this year: <u>The Manager's Path</u> by Camille Fournier, <u>Shantaram</u> by Gregory

David Roberts, and <u>Sapiens</u> by Yuval Noah Harari